[Groaning]
[Gasps]
[Breathing heavily]
[Whimpering]
[Screams]
[Chattering]
Morning. Cassie.
Glad you could join us.
Sorry I'm late.
Hi.
Good morning.
Kid's late again.
Okay. you have a good day.
Mr. Rodriguez.
[Mr. rodriguez]
Thanks. You. too.
Hey. what took you so long?
I thought you left the house
right after me.
I did.
Traffic was unbelievable.
Okay. I'll log you in.
Go get your drawer.
No. Mom. please.
I got it.
Cassie. honey.
I know you want
to stay up all night
and talk with
your friends online.
but you can't come in here
20 minutes late all the time.
Mom. this is. like.
the second time
this has ever happened.
Just relax.
Actually.
it's the third.
If it happens
one more time.
Mr. crenshaw's
gonna let you go.
He said that?
Why doesn't he just
tell me to my face?
Because I'm the one
that convinced him
to hire you.
That is so
passive-aggressive.
[Female dispatcher on radio]
Unit 6. what's your 20?
Unit 6 at union
and west kalmia.
Okay. you may not need
this job. but I do.
Oh. so I'm making you look bad?
Is that what you're saying?
If I'm such an embarrassment
to you. then why do you
force me to work here?
Force you? Do you know
how many kids your age
are out of work?
Besides. I thought you wanted
to save for college.
You know. lately.
I don't know about college.
You promised me
you would enroll
at the j.C. This fall.
Maybe I changed my mind.
[Scoffs]
When are you gonna get serious?
Here we go again.
You don't want to work.
You don't wanna go to college
like the rest of your friends.
Look. I don't care
what you do with your time.
Just find something...
Anything
you're passionate about...
and do it.
Mom. can we talk
about this at home?
I'm at work.
Ugh! You remind me
so much of your father
it's not even funny.
Look...
Turn around.
What... no.
Your hair's...
I don't need your help!
Your name tag's
upside down.
Mom. I didn't mean it.
I just...
I'm sorry.
You're right.
It's just...
Sometimes I forget.
What?
That you're all grown up.
[Chuckles]
Look. I know it's corny.
but to me. you're...
Always gonna be
my baby girl.
I can help
who's next in line.
[Whispers]
It's not corny.
Oh. God. Mom...
[Man]
We're being hit!
[Yelling]
Don't shoot!
Mom...
[altered voice
through speaker device]
Go!
Move!
Yes.
Step away
from the counters. now!
Stay down!
Stay down. Stay down.
Open the door!
Three seconds.
and I'll shoot him!
Nobody move!
[Gasps]
[Voice altered
through speaker device]
Take out your cell phones. now!
Toss them on the floor!
All of them!
Get down!
All the phones!
Let's go!
Hurry up!
Do it!
All right.
Everybody into the vault.
Let's go.
Go. go. go!
Go! Get up! Go!
Okay. All right.
Move it! Let's go!
Go. go. go. go. go!
Okay. Wait...
Go. go! Faster!
Go! Hurry up!
Ow. ow!
Wait a minute.
You come with me.
Mom!
Get in there!
Stay there!
Mom!
[Screaming. yelling]
Get over here.
Please don't hurt them.
Please. I'll do
whatever you want.
You do everything I say.
exactly how I tell you. okay?
Okay. Yeah.
Move it!
Are you crazy?
My daughter's out there.
They'll shoot you both.
I'll take my chances.
Now give me that key!
Hurry up! All of it.
Put it in the bag.
Right on time.
Let's go.
Listen to me.
Go outside and let them in.
Do whatever
you normally do.
Don't try to give them
any kind of funny signal.
'cause if you do.
I'll shoot you in the back.
Go!
Good morning. Cassie.
Good morning.
How's your day going?
Really good. You?
Another day giving 100%
to the top 1%
so they can keep me
in the bottom 10%.
How's your mom?
She's good.
That woman
deserves a promotion.
Five years working
for this company.
and I bet she hasn't missed
a single day.
Kind of makes you wonder
why the hell
we even do this crap.
Where is everybody?
[Grunts]
[Whimpering]
[Exhales]
Bob. please.
they have my daughter.
I cannot
just stay in here.
What if it
was your daughter?
Hurry up.
Gotta make sure.
Hey. John.
you all clear?
Hey. John. do you copy?
Give me the "all clear."
buddy.
Bob. please.
I'm sorry. I can't.
Give me that key!
Dispatch.
officer's radio is 10-3.
I'm going inside
to check it out.
[Grunts]
Where are you going?
[Grunts. groans]
Put the money
in the bag!
Hurry up! Go!
[Groaning continues]
Robbery in progress.
Shots fired.
[Dispatcher]
Copy that. unit 6.
Police en route.
The zipper's stuck.
What? You kidding me?
Why are you doing this?
Let's go.
[Man]
Oh. watch out.
[Woman]
What are you doing?
Be careful.
Whoa. Whoa. whoa.
Watch out.
Get in the back
of the van. quick!
[Gunshot]
No. don't!
Hey!
What the hell
is the matter with you?
[Grunting]
Stop it!
Take it easy!
Come on! Stop it!
[Sighs]
Wait a second.
I've seen you before.
From school.
You graduated last year.
She didn't graduate.
She got kicked out.
Grace?
Hi. Cassie.
Why is she here?
She recognized me.
Oh. that's great.
Just great.
Are you out
of your mind?
What the hell
is going on?
[Grunting]
How much you get?
Probably twice as much
as we expected.
but so what?
A hostage. abbie?
Seriously?
I had to.
She was not
part of the plan.
Yeah? Well. bringing live ammo
wasn't part of the plan. either.
Wait. You did that?
Yeah. And she shot the guy
from the armored truck.
Oh. my God.
We killed somebody.
We didn't kill him.
He was moving when I
ran out of the truck.
I can't believe it.
We're screwed!
Everybody just chill. okay?
We're not screwed.
It's a black market gun.
I made sure to cover my ass.
unlike abbie over here.
who stupidly decided
to bring her best friend along...
Her best friend
who's gonna talk.
She won't.
She knows us.
She will.
What were
you thinking. Joyce?
You could've got us
all killed.
[Chattering]
[Police radio chatter]
Good morning.
ladies and gentlemen.
I am f.B.I. Agent
Christine mendoza.
and I'm gonna be leading
this investigation.
which means I'm gonna
have to speak to each
and every one of you.
So please don't leave
the premises.
Folks.
I'm detective barker.
Please have a seat
in the sterile holding area
over here.
Detective. I'm Joyce aveson.
If you need medical help...
My daughter...
ma'am. please.
We'll be with you in a moment.
Just take a seat.
They kidnapped my daughter.
Come with me.
I swear to God.
if you tell the cops I did this.
I'll tell them you helped abbie
plan this whole thing.
which you practically did.
Knock it off!
We hold Cassie until tonight.
That'll give us time.
You can go get out of the state.
and I can do what I gotta do.
[Girls grunt]
What the hell
are you doing?
Taking the back way.
The cops will be looking for us
on the main road.
[Girls grunt]
What does she mean.
that I helped you plan this?
Abbie. what does
she mean by that?
Forget it.
The less you know. the better.
Don't listen to Marie.
She's full of crap.
Watch your mouth.
Wait just a minute.
So a couple weeks ago.
when you were asking me
all those questions
about the bank...
My schedule.
how many employees
are there.
the vault. what time
the armored truck arrives...
I thought that you
just wanted a job.
I was trying
to help you.
And you sure as hell did.
Shut up. Marie!
I trusted you.
I'm sorry.
And you set me up.
How could you guys
do this to me?
Cassie. take it easy.
Why. abbie?
I had to!
Grace. stop the van right now.
I'm getting out.
Okay. cool.
So you're gonna let her
call the shots now.
Is that what
you're gonna do. grace?
Grace!
Cassie. calm down!
Grace. do it now!
[Grace]
Cassie...
[clamoring]
Oh. my God!
[Grunting. yelling]
An armored car driver
was shot this morning
as two heavily armed men
wearing ski masks
held up the palm vista bank
here on the 2300 block
of El cajon boulevard
in downtown San Diego.
The robbery happened
right around 9:30 A.M..
just under an hour ago.
Fortunately. the driver
sustained only minor bruising
due to the bulletproof vest
he was wearing at the time.
According to
the bank's manager.
the two masked men escaped
with an undisclosed
amount of money
and were last seen
driving away from the bank
in a green van.
Must be nice
to work with your daughter.
[Joyce]
It is.
I got her the job
to spend more time with her.
Her dad died of colon cancer
when she was ten.
Sorry to hear that.
I haven't really
been there for her.
Maybe I was the reason
she was getting
into trouble at school.
What kind of trouble?
Oh. she was suspended.
For what?
Fighting.
Takes after her mom.
Well. I hear this morning
in the vault.
you and your boss
got into it.
Yeah. I was trying
to help Cassie.
So you interrupted
an armored car driver
who attempted
to stop the getaway?
Yes. He was aiming
toward my daughter.
I understand
how you feel.
I'm sorry.
As a mother.
I believe I have the right
to protect my child.
But you forget.
these armored car drivers
are trained to handle
the situation.
Do you have children.
Ms. mendoza?
No.
Well. then. forgive me when
I tell you that you're wrong.
Because there's
no possible way
you could understand
how I feel.
[Barker]
Mendoza.
We got the surveillance video
cued up.
Please stay put.
[Sniffles]
[Chuckles]
Is everybody okay?
I need help.
[Coughing]
Easy.
I think
I messed up my leg.
Okay.
[Grunting]
You okay?
Cassie!
[Panting]
Cassie. stop!
Cassie! Cassie!
Get off of me!
Cassie. please stop!
This is how
you pay me back?
What?
For last semester
in the locker room?
I can't even believe
you're bringing that up.
I got suspended for fighting.
for defending you.
and this is how you thank me?
This is the thanks I get?
You almost killed us.
Marie...
I ought to pop you
right now!
Come on. Take it easy.
I told you she'd try to run
to the cops.
She can't afford to.
Like you said.
if she goes to the cops.
we'll say she was in on it.
We'll say
she's the insider.
But that'll never happen.
because she's gonna
do what I say.
Right. Cassie?
Right.
Grace and abbie...
They might be your friends.
Don't confuse them
with me.
Come on.
[Grunts]
[Mendoza]
Okay. now check this out.
Freeze.
Does that look weird
to you?
Yeah.
Play it again.
Right there.
She says something.
Why are you doing this?
What do you think?
I think I'm gonna go talk
to the mother again.
We need to pull everything
out of the van
and wipe it down.
You do that.
I'm getting my money.
I... I think
I broke my leg.
The bone is popping out.
I am so sorry
I grabbed the wheel.
I should never
have done that.
Shut up.
Take this.
Start picking up
the money. Go.
Abbie. we gotta
get outta here.
Yeah. No kidding.
Someone might see us.
I got it handled.
How?
I said I got it handled.
Go.
[Barker]
A moment prior.
she's cowering in fear.
Then.
suddenly she stands.
and they stare
at each other
for nearly
ten whole seconds.
Now. I'm no psychologist.
but I'd say given the proximity.
they seem pretty comfortable
with each other.
That could mean anything.
You have no idea
the emotional hell
she was going through
at that moment.
Actually. I do.
Were you there?
He was aiming a gun
at her. point-blank.
Ms. aveson. I spent
ten years at the border
during
the Mexican drug wars.
El Paso. matamoros.
Tijuana.
I've seen more
than my fair share
of hostage situation.
kidnapping attempts
and beheadings.
Great resume.
You wanna impress me?
Find my daughter.
I think
they know each other.
What?
[Barker]
It adds up.
Body language.
the way they talk to each other.
ten seconds
of visual recognition.
You have got
to be kidding me.
A dozen people in a vault.
Your daughter
is the only one chosen
to empty the cash drawers
and escort the courier
from the armored car.
They grabbed
the last person
to go into the vault.
That just so happened
to be Cassie.
You show me a video
of these bastards
sticking a loaded gun
into my baby girl's face.
and then you try and tell me
that she's working with them.
Are you crazy?
We'll talk about this later.
Please excuse us.
[Sighs]
[Whimpering]
Let me check yours.
abbie.
We'll do it later.
Don't worry.
You'll get your cut.
My God. Marie!
You called your boyfriend?
What did you tell him?
Everything.
I kind of had to.
That was not
part of the plan.
Baby. baby!
Nobody's supposed
to know about this!
[Laughing]
Come here.
You all right?
Let's see what you got.
Oh. my God.
Oh. yeah! That's what
I'm talking about. Whoo!
[Laughs]
Hey. Nick.
How'd you get here
so fast?
You live across town.
A shortcut.
Who's this
little sport-rocket?
Shut up.
She's not your type.
[Chuckles]
[Marie]
Let's go.
Bye.
[Groaning]
We have to get her
to a hospital now.
I know.
Come on.
God. let's get
the hell out of here.
Up you go.
[Nick laughing]
Come on.
We gotta get somewhere.
Here.
I got you.
Come on. come on. come on.
[Nick laughing]
Come on.
Yeah!
Okay. Be careful.
[Nick]
Yeah! Whoo!
[Chattering]
[Click]
[Printer whirrs]
What's taking her
so long?
[Scoffs]
She's probably updating
her Facebook page.
"Hey. everybody.
I just robbed a bank!
O.M.G.! So much fun!"
[Laughs]
You're not funny. Nick.
So. why is it that
they brought you along?
Your driving skills?
Oh. kiss my ass.
Abbie needed help.
I was the first person
she called.
Was this worth the money?
We didn't do it
for the money.
Hey!
I think they
know each other.
[Yelling]
Whoo!
Wow. Nice.
When can we take her
to the emergency room?
Don't worry about it.
Abbie. you do what
you have to do. okay?
[Groans]
I promise I will get you there
as soon as I possibly can.
Okay.
That's them.
Hello. abbie.
You got the money?
It's right here.
Bueno.
Where's my dad?
[spanish]
[Man grunts]
Daddy.
I'm okay. honey.
They hurt you.
It looks worse than it is.
Are you all right?
I did what they asked.
What?
Oh. my God.
Where did you get all that?
Don't worry about it.
I'm gonna
bring you home. okay?
Just be strong
another couple of hours.
Abbie. what did you do?
Dad?
You bring $500.000
a coyote pass.
off highway 98.
12 Miles east of ocotillo.
You park at the road block.
then hike in half a mile.
Okay.
At the old water tank.
you're gonna see a road.
Wait for us there.
Okay.
4:00. You come alone.
No cops.
Do exactly like I say.
or he dies.
Oh. and I'm gonna keep
your papa's computer.
I like it.
[Clicks off]
[Crying]
Hey. I just got a call
from the station.
It looks like
they might have found
the getaway van.
Where's the mom?
Haven't seen her.
[Cassie]
So how did it happen?
You know how my dad
does real estate
in foreign countries?
Three weeks ago.
he went down to Tijuana.
He said they grabbed him
right off the street.
Drug cartel. mafia...
I have no clue who they are.
But they called me
and told me
that I had to give them
a half a million dollars
by today.
or they would kill him.
Pretty good scam.
if you ask me.
Who's asking?
Ow. ow. ow.
Sorry.
Why didn't you
just go to the police?
You heard what he said.
If I go to the cops.
they will kill him.
Aren't they in Mexico?
I mean. how would they
even know?
They told me that
if I tell the cops.
the cops will tell the feds.
and the feds will tell
the Mexican government.
and they would find out.
because they have people
working inside
the Mexican government.
Okay. so. why didn't you
just use your own money?
Your father's. like.
a millionaire. right?
This house alone
must be worth. like...
zip.
Mortgaged to the hilt.
My dad lost everything
in the recession.
We have nothing.
[Marie]
Boo-hoo.
Poor little rich girl.
forced to live
like the rest of us.
Ever since I lost my mom.
it's just been me
and my dad.
I didn't have anybody else
to turn to.
Why didn't you
just come to me
instead of doing all this
behind my back?
If I had.
would you have helped me
rob the bank?
That is 370.000
United States currency. baby.
and that's just
what's in this bag.
Whoo! Give me the bag
so I can check the rest of it.
Let go. Marie.
No. you let go.
[Grunts]
What was that?
Someone pulled
in front of your house.
It's Cassie's mom.
Mom...
Grace...
[muffled shouts]
She saw me!
Hurry up!
Put Cassie in the bedroom!
Nick. get the money
off the table!
You kidding me? I just
finished stacking this up.
Nick. now!
No. I don't think so.
Bring me the other bag.
I'll count it.
Abbie!
Hurry up! Go! Now!
Freaking kidding me.
Come on. come on. come on!
[Joyce]
Abbie!
I know you're in there!
[Groaning]
Easy.
Please open this door.
If you say a word
you're dead.
If your mom walks
through that door right now.
I'm gonna shoot her in the face.
[Joyce]
Abbie!
Ow!
Here. Right there.
Abbie. I need to talk
to you now. please.
You know that I saw you.
Please open this door.
What are you doing?
Abbie!
Everybody be really quiet.
Hi. Joyce.
Good morning.
Hi. Abbie. I don't suppose
your dad's home?
Mm-mm. He's on
a business trip. Why?
Where's Cassie?
W... um. she's not here.
Abbie. don't lie to me.
I'm not lying.
Is Cassie in some kind
of trouble or something?
I don't know.
Is she?
You're really starting
to scare me.
What is going on?
I think you know
exactly what's going on.
I do? Because I...
Cassie!
What... hang on!
Wait... no.
She's with you. right?
She's working today.
Stop with the act.
I know you were
at the bank today.
Where is she?
At the bank.
She's not at the bank.
You took Cassie hostage.
What?
I could've told the police.
I didn't.
All I want is my daughter.
Please. Where is she?
Joyce. slow down.
[Whispering]
I saw a big roll of plastic
in the garage.
We dig a hole in the desert.
get rid of both of them.
[Whispering]
Shut up.
[No audible dialogue]
What is that?
This is a still frame
from security video
at the bank.
This is the wrist
of the person who robbed us
this morning.
My God. are you okay?
Was anybody hurt?
Abbie. stop it.
I was with Cassie
when she bought that for you.
A million people
have bracelets like that.
Cut the bull!
No offense.
but are you on. like.
some kind of medication
or something?
Because none of this
makes any sense.
A few weeks ago.
Cassie told me
you were asking her
a lot of questions
about her job.
Yeah?
Why were you so curious?
Joyce. be real.
Do you really think
that I'm the kind of girl
who would rob a bank?
You're telling me
that you have been here
all morning. alone?
Yeah.
Prove it.
I guess you're just gonna
have to take my word for it.
No. I'm gonna look
in every room in this house.
I'm gonna go out there
and shoot her right now.
Wait. wait.
Cassie?
Get in the bathroom.
Cassie. are you back here?
Wait! Joyce. wait!
Ms. aveson. please!
Cassie.
are you back here?
Wait!
Oh. Hey.
Baby. what's going on?
Um...
This is. um...
This is my friend's mom.
Oh. hi. I'm Jack.
[Nick. abbie chuckle]
Babe. why don't you
go back to bed?
I'll be in
in a minute.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Mm.
[Sighs]
I love you.
I love you. too.
[Chuckles]
I can't get
enough of this.
[Laughs]
[Nick. abbie chuckle]
I'm sorry I lied.
I wasn't alone.
Please don't
tell my dad.
I guess I owe you
an apology.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
You've been through
a lot this morning.
What about Cassie?
Do the police have any idea
where they took her?
No. not yet. Um...
The cops said that
once the bank robbers
get far enough away.
they usually
let the hostage go.
But I guess I'll just
have to wait and see.
I'm really sorry.
What's this...
Coyote pass off highway 98?
Oh. that's just
a message for my dad.
Some guy called about
some kind of development
out in the desert.
I'll have to remember
to give that to him.
I'll let myself out.
[Wincing]
[Sighs]
She's gone!
[Mutters]
[Grunts]
Go!
Hey. that's twice today
I've saved your bacon.
Least you could do
is say "thank you."
I'm not sensing
gratitude right now.
No.
I think abbie
needs to learn
that it's better to give
than receive.
[Cassie]
Abbie...
We're taking it all.
We had a deal.
I changed the deal.
Marie. please.
Between your bag and mine.
I'm sure we've got over
a million dollars right now.
Our agreement was to keep
everything over 500.000.
That's not enough for you?
I've expensive taste.
Okay. what about abbie's dad?
You saw what they did to him.
If they don't get
the money they asked for.
they're gonna kill him.
That's abbie's problem.
not mine.
Let's go.
I say we kill all three of them.
cover our tracks.
It's not required.
What if they talk?
Then they'll get 30 to life
for armed robbery.
They're stupid.
but they're not that stupid.
Come on.
Let's hit it.
Marie.
Come on.
You think you're better
than me. don't you?
Come on.
What's happening?
We need to get outta here
right now.
Why?
Because Nick and Marie
are gonna be back any second.
and this time.
they will kill us.
Move.
But...
Mm.
[Sighs]
When we get
to the hotel in Reno.
I'm gonna throw this money
all over the bed.
Oh. yeah?
Mm-hmm.
And then I'm gonna
throw you on top of it...
[Chuckles]
And then I'm gonna
take off my...
What the hell is this?
[Yells]
You gotta be kidding me.
[Marie screaming]
I'm gonna kill her!
[Screams]
Cassie. I'm gonna drop you off
a couple blocks away
from the hospital.
I know that I have no right
to ask you for a favor.
but can you please wait
to talk to the cops
until after 4:00?
Just give me that time
to get my dad back.
Can you promise me that?
Yes. Yeah.
I'm just worried about...
Abbie. let's go.
Okay.
We're gonna take my dad's car
so grace can fit
in the back seat.
[Grunts]
[Yells]
Okay.
Hold on.
hold on. hold on.
Damn it!
The car is gone!
Check upstairs.
Yeah.
They're not here.
[Yells]
[Police radio chatter]
[Mendoza]
So what exactly did you see?
Well.
there were four women
who came from the van.
and then they walked
up that hill. and...
A brown truck arrived.
and a man stepped out.
and then everyone got in.
They drove off.
Women? You're sure?
Yes. I'm pretty sure I know
what a woman looks like. dear.
What age were they?
Well. the guy
was in his late 20's.
and the girls
were college age.
High school. maybe.
And what ethnicity
were they?
Well. they were all white.
except one girl
was African-American.
Looks like
she'd broken a leg.
They were helping her walk.
This is a long shot.
but any of the girls
look like this?
You know. I was standing
all the way over there.
I'm not sure...
Yes. Possibly.
Yes. one girl
did look like her.
Okay.
Thank you. Mrs. Wells.
Agent mendoza.
before you leave.
maybe you could help me.
I'm looking
for someone.
His name is Gary.
Gary Wells.
He's seven years old.
He should be back by now.
but I haven't seen him yet.
I'm very. very worried.
and I want you
to look for him. please.
Okay. I'll do that.
I'll wait for your call.
All right.
I want you to alert every
emergency room in the area
to be on the lookout
for an African-American girl.
18 to 25.
with a sprained ankle
or a broken leg.
Whoa. Wait a minute.
You don't actually believe
what she said?
My grandfather
was the same way.
One second. he'd be sharp.
The next second.
he'd be...
Floating off
to another planet.
Not gonna
hold up in court.
[Cassie]
How did you know
they would rob you?
I didn't.
But when we flipped the van.
Nick came to pick us up
way too fast.
And then when we got home.
I saw footprints in the house.
and the back door
was unlocked.
I always lock that door.
My guess is.
while we
were robbing the bank.
Nick broke into the house
and was waiting
to ambush us when we got there.
But then Marie called him
to come pick us up.
Yeah?
Come get us.
We crashed the van.
You what?
You heard me!
You got the money. right?
Shut up. and get over
to the old dirt road!
Yeah. I'll be right there.
Regardless.
he and Marie were planning
to screw me over all along.
So while you guys were waiting
outside in the car.
I counted the cash.
and I put it underneath
the bathroom sink
and replaced it with
my dad's paperback collection.
Hello. This is Joyce.
Mrs. aveson.
this is detective mendoza.
I've got some new evidence
involving your daughter.
What is it?
I'd like to discuss it
in person.
Can you meet me at
the f.B.I. Headquarters
on 3rd street?
One last favor:
When you talk to the police.
leave grace's name out of it.
Um. hello! Thank you.
Cassie.
I don't have that long.
Are you really gonna
go talk to the kidnappers
without any protection at all.
like a gun or anything?
Do I have a choice?
I mean.
my life's over.
I'm gonna go to jail
either way.
But I'm gonna try to get
my dad back first.
I'll see you later.
Okay.
I'm coming with you.
[Grunts]
Cassie...
Just shut up and drive.
[Joyce]
So when do you think
this happened?
According to eyewitnesses.
the car crashed
at about 10:30 A.M..
45 minutes
after the robbery.
But by the time we got there.
the car was already abandoned.
Do you know if Cassie
was with them?
Somebody who looks
like your daughter
was seen there.
along with a man
in his late 20's
and three girls
approximately Cassie's age.
one of whom
had a broken leg.
Ms. aveson. three teenage girls
robbed your bank this morning.
The reason I called you
in here today
is 'cause I need to talk to you
about Cassie's friends.
I'm gonna need a list from you
of names. e-mail addresses...
No. Cassie's friends
are all going to college.
Trust me. they're not
spending their summer break
robbing banks.
Are you sure about that?
Tell you what. um.
why don't you give me
a list of names.
and I'll confirm whether Cassie
knows them or not.
That's the way it's
supposed to work. isn't it?
I'm just trying to help you.
The best thing
you can do right now
for your daughter
is give me as much information
as possible
so that "a"
we can find her.
and "b" we can rule out
any connection
with the bank job.
And if I don't?
Well. then.
the evidence just stacks up
against the both of you.
Excuse me?
That little stunt
you pulled this morning
with the armored car driver.
covering up for her now...
How do I know
you're not the insider?
you're not orchestrating
this whole thing?
Okay.
I get it.
And now I won't
be discussing this
any further with you
without a lawyer.
Please. it's just
a list of names.
That's all I'm asking.
[Sighs]
[Wincing]
So what happened to you?
I was hiking.
and I guess I wasn't watching
where I was going.
Okay. on "three."
One. two. three.
I guess you're not
gonna do that again.
Thank you.
You watch her back. okay?
Yeah.
Ortho room.
Wet-to-dry dressing.
[T.V. Chatter]
Come on.
Ladies.
Hi. I'm gonna need you both
to fill out some forms.
Can't grace just do that?
This is for
insurance purposes.
They're gonna want as many
third-party statements
as possible.
Why don't you have a seat.
and I'll go get the paperwork?
We don't really have time.
It's only gonna take a minute.
It's gonna help your friend out.
Okay.
We'll come back later.
[T.V. Chatter continues]
Excuse me. ladies.
Can I have a word with you
in my office. please?
Uh...
Uh. what's wrong?
I just need to ask you
a few questions.
Why?
Just routine.
Nothing to worry about.
Please.
Follow me.
We just came
to drop off our friend.
[Woman]
The getaway van was found
overturned and abandoned...
I'm sorry.
I can't let you do that.
On the security camera.
where we can see
one of the robbers
stuffing the money
into a green duffle bag.
The robbers left with one of
the bank employees. and...
Run!
No. they were here.
They just ran by
my security officer.
Go. go. go!
[Security]
Out of the way!
Move it! Move it!
Move it!
[Man]
Whoa... what...
watch out.
[People exclaiming]
Get out of the way!
[Grunts]
[Groaning]
[Panting]
Come on! Come on!
Okay.
Let's hurry up.
[Man] Yeah.
Security tried to stop them.
but they got away.
Okay. Thanks.
I'm on my way
to the hospital right now.
All right.
See you soon.
Okay.
What? Is it them?
They call from
a different number every time.
Hello?
[Man]
Hey. chica.
We just watched
American t.V.
Somebody robbed
the palm vista national bank
and got away
with a million dollars
in a green bag.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
You think I estúpido?
I tell you what I think.
I think you got
a million dollars.
and you're not telling us.
I don't have a million.
I have 600.000 or so.
but that's it.
The price just went up.
You wanna see your papa alive.
you meet us at the border
in 90 minutes.
you bring us a million dollars.
You can't do this.
I did what you asked.
One million.
Don't be late.
or I chop off his head.
Gracias.
What they'd say?
Abbie. what is going on?
I did what
they told me to do.
I pull of the impossible.
and then they change the rules
at the very last minute?
Well...
God. those sons of bitches!
Now they want
a million dollars.
There's nothing I can do.
My dad's gonna die.
and there's nothing I can do.
No. No. He is not
gonna die. okay?
We'll get the money.
How?
We can't rob
your bank twice.
Can we?
Her name's Cassie aveson.
She goes to your high school.
Do you know her?
I know of her.
We're not friends.
if that's what you're asking.
That's interesting.
because the admitting nurse
and the security guard
said that this girl
was the girl who admitted you
in this hospital
less than an hour ago.
They're mistaken.
My friends Barbara and Nancy
dropped me off.
Really?
So why do you think
Nancy and Barbara
ran from
the security guard?
Sometimes they smoke
a little weed.
Maybe they had some on them
and didn't wanna get busted.
Where'd you go hiking
this morning?
Torrey pines.
You sure you weren't here?
'Cause my witnesses said
that Cassie was helping
an African-American girl
with a broken leg
out of a van this morning
that just so happened to be
the same van
used in the getaway
at the bank robbery.
How long you gonna
play this game. grace?
You're a smart woman.
School principal says
you're going to Stanford.
gonna be a lawyer.
Good for you.
You should know better
than to get messed up
in something like this.
I know you were with Cassie
this morning.
Who else?
Come on. grace.
If you cooperate with me.
that's gonna take
the edge off. you know?
It's your first offense.
You're gonna do
a short sentence.
But if you don't.
I'm gonna make sure
you do hard time
for armed robbery
and attempted murder.
Do you understand
those legal terms. counselor?
All right.
I'll talk.
Okay. Good.
All right.
Start with this morning.
I wanna know everything.
Go.
I. um...
I woke up.
Did some reading.
"No person shall be held
to answer on a capital.
"or otherwise infamous crime.
unless on a presentment
or indictment
of a grand jury."
Fifth amendment?
I'm not gonna say.
[Sighs]
[Grunts]
[Nick]
Just shut up. all right?
I'm sick of hearing about it.
You were holding it.
All you had to do
was look inside.
We bagged 370.000. all right?
We're going to Reno.
just like we planned.
I want the rest of it.
We know where abbie's
gonna be at 4:00.
I'm not mixing it up
with pancho villa
and his band
of mariachi mutilators.
All right? I won't.
Well. I've got it
all figured out. so...
If you did.
I don't wanna hear about it.
Okay. Remember:
One honk. I go in;
and two.
you get out of there.
Okay?
Okay.
Listen to me!
We get to the border early.
We grab the cash from abbie
before the kidnappers show up.
There isn't enough time.
There isn't enough time!
I wanna be on the road
in the next 30 minutes.
just like we planned.
Pack your stuff.
Douche face.
I thought I said
I wasn't talking to you.
[Mendoza]
Grace Miller. 18 years old.
African-American.
senior editor
of the school newspaper.
That ring a bell?
Um...
She's at the adobe park
hospital medical center
with a broken leg.
My guess is she probably broke
her leg when the van flipped.
Part of the robbery.
I've been trying
to get her to talk
for the last 20 minutes.
and she's not
saying anything.
That's why I called you.
Is Cassie
friends with grace?
Ms. aveson?
I. uh... I don't know.
You sound unsure.
She's mentioned the name.
grace Miller. in passing.
but just like
any other girl in school.
So. no. I don't know
if they're actually friends.
I guess you'll
just have to ask Cassie
when you finally get around
to locating her.
You know.
I may not be a mom.
but if I were.
I think I'd know
who my kid hangs out with.
In fact. I'd probably know
everything about her life.
I'd search her room
for drugs from time to time.
because you never know
what she might be up to.
I'll take that
into consideration.
And I'll call you
if I get any more names.
Mmm.
It's her.
That was one
sneaky-ass move. abbie.
We need to talk.
I'm listening.
I don't need any long-term
trouble from you guys.
so I wanna
work out a truce.
What kind of truce?
You've got 370.000.
I've got 650.000.
I'm willing to put up 150k
for you guys to back off.
Half a million for each of us.
No hard feelings.
Interested?
We're interested.
Then it's a deal.
No changing your mind.
No changing my mind.
Okay.
I'm out front of your house.
Stay on the line.
Okay.
We're outside.
Where are you?
Why don't you come inside.
have a beer. talk it over?
Actually.
let's do it outside.
Fine. Come here.
You guys come to me.
I've got the cash in the trunk.
All right.
[Grunts]
Come on!
Whoa. whoa. whoa. whoa.
What the...
[Mutters]
Little bitch.
Nick!
[Breathing heavily]
Stay out here!
Watch the front door!
[Gasps]
Stop!
[Screams]
[Pounding on door]
Open the door!
[Grunting]
[Keys jingle]
Nick?
[Nick]
You see her?
No.
Well. she's in here
somewhere.
[Sighs]
[Floor creaks]
Aahh!
[Gasps]
[Whimpers]
[Crying]
Shhh.
Oh. my God.
Shhh. It's okay.
It's okay.
Abbie. come on.
We gotta go.
We're gonna go
get your dad. so...
We just gotta
get outta here.
Abbie. come on.
We gotta get out of here.
[Sighs]
What do you think
they're gonna do
when they find the bodies?
It'll look like
a drug deal gone wrong.
There are probably
20 guys out there
that would love
to see Nick dead.
So you wanna tell me
what happened?
[Nick groaning]
[Chuckles]
Oh. you don't
have it in you.
[Yells]
[Footsteps]
[Gasps]
[Yells]
I... no.
Okay.
[Chattering]
Hi. grace.
How you feeling?
Hi. Mrs. aveson.
Uh. great.
They're gonna operate
in the morning.
Where's your mom?
She's on her way.
She had to work
up in Oakland today.
Those are pretty.
Where'd you get them?
Uh. my dining room table.
Sorry. I didn't have time
to go to the florist.
But strawberry.
banana. pineapple.
with protein powder
and a vitamin dose.
Wow. How'd you know
this was my favorite?
'Cause you and Cassie
always get the same thing.
You have for years.
Where is she?
The f.B.I. Knows
you were involved.
What I don't get...
Why would someone like you.
about to go to one of
the top universities
in the country.
want to rob a bank?
Do you need money
for tuition?
Grace. please.
tell me what's going on.
As I was driving here.
I was thinking
I should prepare some
really clever argument
to convince you to talk.
but I couldn't come up
with anything.
All I know is. uh...
My husband's gone now.
Cassie's my whole life.
I make her breakfast. um...
I. uh...
On mondays.
I wash her clothes.
I pay her car insurance
when she forgets.
[Crying softly]
I want to. uh.
help pick out her classes
for college. and. uh...
I really hope
she goes to college.
I wanna see her find
a career she really loves.
and. uh...
Grace. I really wanna
see her get married.
This morning.
someone in a mask
put a gun to her head.
and I couldn't
do anything.
I'm her mother.
and my job
is to protect her.
and I couldn't
do anything.
Is that the last time
I'm going to see her?
Oh. grace. please.
I don't know where she is.
I don't know
if she's been taken from me.
or if she's just
running away from me
or what is going on.
So please. please!
Please. grace.
just tell me what's going on.
I love her so much.
And I love you and abbie.
I always have.
ever since you were little
and I coached you in soccer.
Remember that?
We never won one game.
but we had a lot of fun. right?
Please.
I am so sorry
about all this.
I... I can't say anything.
but if it's any help.
just know this whole thing
will be over in 45 minutes.
That's 4:00.
What's happening
at 4:00?
Coyote pass.
off of highway 98.
They're going to the desert.
Grace. why?
Why are they going there?
I can't say.
[Panting]
[Abbie's father]
Abbie. what did you do?
4:00. Don't be late.
or I chop off his head.
There it is.
Right up there.
[Sighs]
Okay. It's gotta be
down there.
Cassie!
[Echoing]
[Gasps]
Mom?
Oh. my God!
Are you okay?
How did you find us?
It wasn't easy.
What are you doing here?
I want the truth.
You need to leave.
Why?
What is going on?
They can't see you.
They'll think it's a trap.
She's right. mom.
"They"? Who's they?
[Stammers]
Girls. I am not budging.
so you better just spit it out.
What is going on?
All right. Abbie's dad
was kidnapped in Tijuana.
and the kidnappers
are gonna be here any minute.
What?
They told me that
I had to give them
a half a million dollars
or they would kill him.
That's why I robbed the bank.
She's telling the truth. mom.
Did you help her?
No. I had no idea she was
doing any of this until today.
Please. don't hate me.
Ms. aveson.
My mom is gone.
and my dad is broke.
I couldn't tell the cops.
What else could I do?
What would you do?
[Cassie]
Mom. you really
have to leave right now.
This is mendoza.
Code 10-31.
I'm at the end
of coyote pass trail
off highway 98.
I'm gonna need backup.
Code 10-31.
[Abbie]
Please. Mrs. aveson.
my dad's life depends on it.
We need to get outta here now.
We'll call the police.
They'll handle it. Come on.
No. I'm not leaving
without my dad!
You and Cassie should just go
and get outta here.
No. we all go together.
No. I'm staying.
You're always bugging me to have
some kind of ambition. right?
To believe in something.
Well. abbie is my best friend.
Oh. jeez.
If I walk out on her
at a time like this.
what kind of a woman am I?
You are gonna be
a dead woman.
and none of
that idealistic garbage
that I taught you
will mean anything.
do you hear me?
Let's go. both of you!
[Vehicle approaching]
[spanish]
Who are you?
This is my friend
and her mom.
I told you
to come alone.
You a cop?
No. I'm just here
to help abbie.
Chaperones.
Pretty ones.
You got the money?
Hey.
[Chuckles]
It looks like
a million to me.
Senorita Duncan.
it was a pleasure
doing business with you.
Maybe we do it again
sometime. yes?
[Laughing]
[Scoffs]
[Mutters]
[Sighs]
[Kidnapper chuckles]
[Father groans]
[Man on radio]
Mendoza. do you copy?
[Gasps]
Who's there?
Who else you bring?
[Stammers]
Federal agents!
Drop your weapons!
Drop your weapons now!
Now! You're
completely surrounded!
Ms. aveson. get down.
Get your people
behind me now.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Where are the other police?
Turn around.
You alone. senora?
Shut up and turn around!
Get down
on your knees now!
[Grunting]
I don't see nobody.
What happened
to your police friends?
They forget about you?
[Mendoza]
Turn around. now!
[Grunting]
[Grunts]
No! Miguelito!
Miguelito.
Miguelito!
[Yells]
[Breathing heavily]
He's getting away!
Let him go.
Get outta here!
Get outta here now!
Go!
I'll get those gringos!
[Grunts]
Mom!
[Yells]
[Grunts]
[Groaning]
Give me that.
So you're my
pretty little bank robber. huh?
I know what
my daughter did was wrong.
She didn't mean
to hurt anybody.
She doesn't deserve
to go to jail.
Please.
She's all I have left.
Is there something
you can do?
Is this
the weapon you used
in the bank robbery?
Well. is it. or not?
Who does the gun
belong to?
Nobody.
It's black market.
It can't be traced.
Are you prepared
to make a statement
that those were the three guys
that kidnapped you this morning?
Oh...
I want you to think
about what I'm asking you.
Cassie.
Yes.
Come on.
[Groans]
Easy.
Careful. Careful.
I still have
some contacts
in Tijuana.
I'm gonna say I got a tip
the robbers were here.
making their way
to the border.
What's that?
Look at
the surveillance video
at the bank.
You'll see.
Come on.
[Grunts]
[Sighs]
Thank you.
I never wanna
see your face again.
[Man on radio]
Agent mendoza. you copy?
Mendoza.
We're 15 minutes out.
I'm gonna need a 10-52.
Copy that.
All right.
The three of you
need to get out outta here.
You. too.
I'm staying
with my daughter.
If I'm gonna pin this bank job
on those three guys.
you're gonna need to leave.
Look. you have no idea
what I have gone through
to try and find her today.
and if you think
for one second...
Mom!
I'm gonna be okay.
[Chuckles]
I guess you will be.
Hey. can I ask you
a question?
Yeah.
If you were
in abbie's situation
and someone you loved
was kidnapped.
and you had to get ahold
of a million dollars.
what would you do?
Me?
I'd probably rob a bank.
[Chuckles]